A Guide to the Papers Pertaining to the Printing of Morley's "Apology for Boccaccio," 1923
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers Pertaining to the Printing of Morley's "Apology for Boccaccio," 1923
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6254-o
This collection consists of 12 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1991 February 14.
Scope and Content Information
The papers contain typescripts, corrected galleys, makereadies, proofs on 18th-century paper and a lay-out copy.
With these are letters from James Shields to H.L. Mencken, H. Byrne Hackett and a Mr. Cox concerning the history of Morley's private edition, variations in the copies and sales.
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - List of Material on Hand Relating to the Printing of Morley's An Apology for Boccaccio1923, TMs. 1 p.
  - An Apology for Boccaccio: Linotyper's copy 1923, TMs. 19 p.
  - An Apology for Boccaccio: Linotyper's copy of the Editorial "Note" 1923, TMs. 8 p.
  - An Apology for Boccaccio: Draft of the Editorial "Note" 1923, TMs. With ink corrections and handwritten notes in both pencil & ink, 4 blue foolscap sheets
  - An Apology for Boccaccio, with one set of the galleys containing pencil corrections by Christopher Morley throughout. 1923, 2 galleys. There are no other sets or copies of these galleys, as only two were pulled, the second for retaining in Philadelphia in case the set sent to Morley for corrections miscarried, 10 sheets each.
  - An Apology for Boccaccio: sixteen "makereadies," thumbed and smeared "as usual" 1923, Makereadies.
  - An Apology for Boccaccio: Final Press-Proofs on slightly foxed sheets of 18th-century paper used for the privately printed edition of eighteen copies, some of the sheets large paper with the original deckle-edge and the rest, the small paper size 1923, proofs.
  - An Apology for Boccaccio: First Dummy or lay-out copy in blank blue sheets, with instructions, paginations, etc., in four sections of sixteen pages each 1923, lay-out copy.
- Letters
  - James Shields to H. L. Mencken 1923 Sep 18, TLS. 2 p., with a blank subscription form for a copy of An Apology for Boccaccio.
    Asks Mencken if he has any objections "to the distribution to a few collector-friends of a privately printed issue of Christopher Morley's essay " An Apology for Boccaccio," which appeared in Smart Set for Nov. 1916 ?" He then goes on to describe the evolution of his plan to print a private edition of the essay entirely on eighteenth century paper made by hand before 1790, numbered and signed by Morley.
  - James Shields to Mr. Cox 1923 Dec 18, TLS. 2 p.
    Offers for sale to Cox's Rare Book Department the material (which he lists in the letter) illustrating the making of a rare and coveted item, the privately printed edition of Morley's essay An Apology for Boccaccio, and also describes the variations in several of the numbered copies of the work.
  - [James Shields] to H. Byrne Hackett 1942 Jul 27, TL. 2 p.
    Offers for sale to Hackett several Eugene Field items and copy number two of the numbered privately printed edition of An Apology for Boccaccio by Christopher Morley which Shields was having illuminated and asks for an expeditious reply.